Finding Aid for the Ray Bradbury Papers LSC.0471
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ray Bradbury papers
1950-1960
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bradbury, Ray
LSC.0471
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
Ray Douglas Bradbury (1920- ) has authored numerous novels, short stories, plays, films, poems, and articles, including he Martian Chronicles (1950), Dandelion Wine, and Something Wicked this Way Comes. The collection consists of manuscripts, correspondence, and ephemera by and related to Ray Bradbury.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ray Bradbury, 1956.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942304073606533
Biography
Ray Douglas Bradbury was born in Waukegan, Illinois, August 22, 1920; started his writing career in 1943; the winner of various awards, he is known primarily for writing fantasy and science fiction stories; he has authored numerous novels, short stories, plays, films, poems, and articles, including The Martian Chronicles (1950), Dandelion Wine, and Something Wicked this Way Comes.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of manuscripts, correspondence, and ephemera by and related to Ray Bradbury. Includes various titles including The Martian Chronicles. Also includes a copy of Moby Dick screenplay and a radio script for the The Whole Town's Sleeping.
Additional Physical Form Available
A copy of the original version of this online finding aid is available at the UCLA Library Special Collections for in-house consultation and may be obtained for a fee. Please contact:
Public Services Division
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library
Box 951575
Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575
Telephone: 310/825-4988 (10:00 a.m. - 4:45 p.m., Pacific Time)
Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu
Related Material
The Dogs That Eat Sweet Grass [oral history transcript] / Ray Bradbury, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1961. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Typescripts.; Authors, American -- Archives.; Bradbury, Ray, 1920-2012--Archives.
- he Martian Chronicles. Published by Doubleday & Company, Garden City, New York, 1950.; Typescript with holograph corrections and printer's notations. 293 leaves. (Box 1)
- he Martian Chronicles., Corrected galley proofs. 66 leaves. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Also: 15 leaves of page proofs with printer's notations (not text).
- Moby Dick. Los Angeles, November 14, 1956.; [Screenplay] Mimeographed. In green paper binder. 148pp. (Box 2)
  Final - but not final shooting script - this is mimeographed copy of script as started October 7, 1953 and finished April 16, 1954 - by R. Bradbury - Huston, later, in shooting film - made some deletions & changes./ R.B.
- The Murderer. In he Golden Apples of the Sun published by Rupert Hart-Davis, London, Manuscript dated, 1953. June 1, 1952.; Typescript with extensive holograph corrections. 17 leaves. In yellow paper binder. (Box 2)
  First draft.
- The April Witch., 31 leaves total. Both typescripts together in green paper binder. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2)
  First draft of first, original, unused version - plus first draft of second, entirely different version - R.B.. Published in Golden Apples of the Sun.
- The Flying Machine., October 17, 1950.; Typescript with corrections. 13 leaves. In orange paper binder. (Box 2)
  First draft. Published in Golden Apples of the Sun.
- And the Rock Cried Out., Typescript (partly carbon). Extensive corrections. (Box 2)
  First 3 drafts of story/ Progressively cut and edited. Published in Farenheit 451 - 1953 by Ballantine Books, Incorporated, New York.
- Summer Night., Typescript (some carbon) and mimeographed. 25 leaves. In yellow paper binder. (Box 3)
  First draft... published in McCalls as The Whole Town's Sleeping/ will appear as part of Doubleday book Dandelion Wine, May 1957.
- he End of the Beginning., Typescript (carbon) with corrections. Second draft. 9 leaves. In yellow paper binder. (Box 2)
  Published in A Medicine for Melancholy, Doubleday, Garden City, New York, 1959.
- The Pipe Organ., Typescript (carbon). 9 leaves. In green paper binder. (Box 2)
  Original version, 1952. Published in A Medicine for Melancholy, 1959, and in Collier's 1954 under the title The Marriage Mender.
- The Magical Kitchen., Typescript with corrections. First leaf has numerous holograph comments and markings on both sides. 12 leaves. In blue paper binder. (Box 2)
  First draft. To appear 1957 in Dandelion Wine.
- The Sound of Thunder. Los Angeles, January 23, 1952.; Typescript (carbon) with extensive corrections. 20 leaves. In yellow paper binder. (Box 3)
  Published in Collier's, 1952.
- The Dwarf., May 28, 1952.; Typescript (partly carbon) with extensive holograph corrections. 25 leaves. In orange paper binder. (Box 2)
  2nd draft. First leaf has explanatory note.
- he Fox in the Forest. Venice, California, February 3, 1950.; Typescript (some carbon) with occasional corrections. 37 leaves. In green paper binder. (Box 2)
  Final draft.
- he Wonderful Death of Dudley Stone., 24 leaves. In orange paper binder. Typescript with extensive corrections. (Box 3)
  Second leaf has many holograph notations and markings and is entitled The Incredible Death of Dudley Stone. Dated June 1952-June 1953.
- he Great Collision of Monday Last., December 9, 1955.; Typescript (carbon). 12 leaves. (Box 2)
  Next to final draft - R.B.
- he First Night of Lent; a one-act play., December 1958-January 1959.; Typescript with extensive corrections. 31 leaves. (Box 2)
- A Wild Night in Ireland., December 16, 1958.; Typescript with some corrections. 12 leaves. (Box 3)
  First draft. Based on a fragment of conversation with Ben Maddow, returned from Ireland, at lunch, December 15, 1958.
- Biographical comments by various persons., 1951-59.; Typescripts. 7 items. In folder. (Box 2)
- Ephemera. Newspapers and magazines with material about and by Ray Bradbury., 7 items. (Box 1)
- Other Worlds; Science Stories. vol.1 no.3 ()., March 1950 (Box 1)
  Contains Punishment Without Crime by Ray Bradbury. pp.6-13.
- Galaxy: Science Fiction. vol.1 no.5 ()., February 1951 (Box 1)
  Contains The Fireman by Ray Bradbury. pp.4-61.
- Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine. vol.32 no.4., October 1958. (Box 1)
  Contains The Town Where no one Got Off by Ray Bradbury. pp.108-114.
- he Science Fiction Galaxy. Permabooks, New York, 1950. (Box 1)
  Contains reprint of King of the Grey Spaces by Ray Bradbury. pp.208-226.
- Correspondence., 1951-.; 17 items. (Box 2)
- Bradbury, Ray, A Medicine for Melancholy. Los Angeles, 1920-. 1959.; Typescript with holograph corrections. 289 leaves. (Box 3)
  First published by Doubleday & Company, Garden City, New York, 1959.
  This is a collection of short stories, previously published in periodicals.
  Final typescript from which type was set.
- --- ---- Another copy., 65 sheets. Galley proofs with corrections in ink. (Box 3)
- --- ---- Another copy., 81 sheets. Page proofs with a few corrections in red pencil. (Box 3)
- --- Interview made by the Oral History Program, UCLA. Los Angeles, 1961.; Typescript (carbon) 462 leaves. 28cm. (Box 3)
  This is the unedited transcript of the tapes, now erased.
  Interview conducted by Craig Cunningham, January 12-April 11, 1961.
  Transcribed by Joyce Doetkott, October 30, 1961-April 11, 1962.
  General note
  Transferred to the University Archives
- --- he Whole Town's Sleeping. n.p., 1958.; Mimeographed with corrections in red and black pencil. 20 leaves. 28cm. (Box 3)
  A radio script broadcast on Suspence, August 31, 1958. This is apparently the copy used by the producer-director, William Robson.